Andrei Biswas

Boston, MA, 02155 | 8579287243 | andrei.biswas@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/andreibiswas | abiswas.dev

PRODUCT MANAGER

I am a musically enthused product manager with 3+ years of diverse tech experience. I create innovative and customercentric solutions, work with teams to solve challenging problems, and learn new skills and technologies to adapt to the evolving world of tech. Additionally, I play and produce music and my original tracks have been streamed over 105,000 times across streaming platforms.

SKILLS

Product management | product development | product marketing | customer research | technical communication | user experience (UX) | Agile methodologies | Scrum | data analysis | cross-functional team leadership | engineering | analytical skills | market research | software development | Python | Java | JavaScript | React | Bash | Git | Azure DevOps | Jira

EXPERIENCE

Product Manager

Microsoft, Cambridge, MA

October 2021 - May 2023

- Grew Intune users by 25% YOY by collaborating with Google engineers to complete the Microsoft 365 and Google
 Workspace productivity vision for personal Android devices, allowing users to sync files across Microsoft 365 and
 Google apps from any device.
- Enhanced device security without admin intervention for millions of Android 12+ devices by investigating, designing, and delivering solutions that follow updated Google password complexity definitions from day 0.
- Retained 150,000 licenses and reduced engineering time by implementing a log collection solution for sovereign cloud customers using Android devices. It leveraged existing UX to minimize development time and boost customer satisfaction.
- Enhanced data security, user privacy, and user transparency for all Intune Android apps by evaluating, designing, and delivering EU-specific data protection in all user scenarios and updated UX accordingly.
- Automated and refined joint enterprise customer support processes for Google and Microsoft partnership, which
 reduced triage time by 50%. It led to faster issue resolution times and improved customer retention.

Program Manager Intern

Microsoft, Cambridge, MA

June 2020 - August 2020

• Used customer evidence to scope feature areas for smartwatch and Android devices' management and gather functional requirements, which involved collaborating with cross-functional teams on multiple projects.

Emerging Technology Engineer Intern Retail Business Services, Quincy, MA

January 2020 - May 2020

- Established the base architecture for the Stop & Shop chatbot on their official website, which serves 4.5 million visitors on average per month and improves customer satisfaction and retention.
- Improved customer feedback process by 20x by implementing a testing infrastructure which enhanced product performance, usability, and customer satisfaction by identifying and resolving issues faster.

Emerging Technology Engineer Intern

January 2019 - August 2019

Retail Business Services, Mooresville, NC

 Built and deployed 4 frictionless checkout prototypes for an Amazon Go-style store with computer vision and Bluetooth, enabling lean cost and setup time to 6 weeks. It enhanced customer satisfaction by offering fresh and healthy food options 24/7 in a fast and convenient way.

Undergraduate Research Assistant

Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, NY

May 2017 - August 2018

Built and deployed an autonomous and real-time monitoring system which labels different machining processes
using sound analysis. It achieved 50% faster and more accurate results than previous system, improving quality
control and error detection.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (B.S.) - Computer Engineering Rochester Institute of Technology, Rochester, NY

August 2016 - May 2021

- Minor in Music and Technology
- Graduated with Magna Cum Laude
- Cumulative GPA: 3.74/4.00 and Major GPA: 3.89/4.00
- Student in the Honors Program, a selective and rigorous program for the top 5% of the university's students